Saikiran Tharimena, PhD

+43-660-687-1497

□ dr.saikirant@gmail.com

Vienna, Austria

in LinkedIn

GitHub

SKILLS

Python

Keras (Tensorflow)

Horovod (multi - GPUs)

Scikit-learn

Pandas

Numpy, Scipy

Matlab

EDUCATION

Ph.D.

University of Southampton, UK 2012 – 2017

M.Sc. (Distinction)

University of Southampton, UK 2011 – 2012

B.Tech. (CGPA 9.06)

Visvesvaraya National Institute of Technology, Nagpur, India 2011 – 2012

CERTIFICATION

IBM Machine Learning Professional

Exploratory Data Analysis
Supervised Learning: Regression
Supervised Learning: Classification
Unsupervised Learning
Deep Learning & Reinforcement Learning
Time Series and Survival Techniques

Nvidia Deep Learning Institute

Fundamentals of Deep Learning Fundamentals of Deep Learning for Multi-GPUs

NASA Academy of Program/Project & Engineering Leadership

Agile Project Management

*click on titles to view certificate credentials

ABOUT ME

A researcher with 6+ years of experience in numerical and statistical modeling, and machine learning. Having garnered invaluable experience in academic research, I am looking forward to switch careers to focus on leveraging the power of machine learning and deep learning to solve real-world challenges.

#Deep Learning #Machine Learning #Statistical Modeling #Data Science

EXPERIENCE

Researcher

Institute for Meteorology & Geophysics / Vienna, Austria / July 2020 - Present

Numerical and waveform modeling for imaging deep earth structure Machine learning and deep learning applications for geophysical exploration

JPL Postdoctoral Fellow

NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory / Pasadena, CA, USA / Feb 2018 - June 2020

3D Full waveform modeling of planetary bodies

Developing tools and methodologies for geophysical exploration of icy moons Planet scale simulation of wavefields at different frequencies

Research Fellow

University of Southampton / Southampton, UK / Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

Seismic network and database management

Waveform modeling of earth structure

Developing novel approaches for leveraging massive datasets

HIGHLIGHTS

Developed the Adaptive Difference Engine

Machine learning algorithm for interpretive modeling of large seismic datasets

Developed tools for 3D full waveform modeling

Collaborator, NASA Mars InSight Mission

High impact research publications in Nature, and Science journals

AWARDS

Dean's award for Research

ILIaD Leadership, Management & Team Management Challenge

Sustainability Action Award

The Royal Astronomical Society research support grant

Vice-Chancellor's Scholarship

Academic Excellence Award